* 3D Printers
    
[* Filament](https://store.bambulab.com/collections/bambu-lab-3d-printer-filament?skr=yes)[* Accessories](https://store.bambulab.com/collections/accessories?skr=yes)* Software
    
[* Support](https://bambulab.com/en/support)* Company

Log In

* Privacy Policy

Effective as of 22 September, 2023

**Before Scrolling Down, Please Read This**
===========================================

Bambu Lab and its global affiliates respect your privacy. We understand that creating a Privacy Policy that satisfies everyone's needs can be challenging. Most people prefer a concise and easy policy. However, legal requirements mandate that we provide detailed information. With that in mind, we’ve tried to make a user-friendly hub with summaries of key topics and a [short version](https://bambulab.com/policies/privacy-short) of this Privacy Policy to empower you to make informed decisions when you use Bambu Lab Products and Services.  

Bambu Lab is a multinational company and the Bambu Lab Products and Services are provided by Bambu Lab and/or its third-party partners. As such, the Personal Data may be collected, processed or accessed by us in countries or regions where you use our products or services, or other countries or regions where we or our affiliates, service providers, or business partners are located. We always aim to ensure that your personal data will be processed to the extent necessary and only for the necessary purposes in accordance with applicable privacy legislation, in particular the General Data Protection Regulation (hereinafter the "**GDPR**") and other applicable privacy laws. The Bambu Lab entities responsible for the processing of personal data including several affiliated companies and specifically the MAKERWORLD SINGAPORE PTE. LTD., an affiliate incorporated in Singapore, as well as the Shenzhen Tuozhu Technology Co., Ltd. and Shanghai Lunkuo Technology Co., Ltd. are the data controllers in the operations to provide the Bambu Lab Products and Services (collectively referred to as "**Bambu Lab**", "**we**", "**us**", or "**our**"). We have appointed Bambulab GmbH to act as our EU Representative pursuant to Article 27 of GDPR. If you wish to exercise your rights under the GDPR, or have any queries in relation to your rights or general privacy matters, please send such information in the format of an email to our Representative at [privacy@bambulab.com](mailto:privacy@bambulab.com). Please ensure to include “Bambulab GmbH” in any correspondence you send to our Representative.

**1\. About this policy**
=========================

The Privacy Policy ("**Policy**") applies when you purchase and/or use the following products or services:

* **Bambu Lab Websites** (such as bambulab.com, Bambu Store, forum.bambulab.com);
* Bambu Lab 3D printers and its filament, accessories and related services ("**Bambu Devices**");
* Bambu Lab Apps (such as Bambu Studio and Bambu Handy) and its cloud-related services ("**Bambu Apps**");
* The 3D Model community available at makerworld.com ("**MakerWorld**");
* Other customer-supporting services provided by Bambu Lab and/or its partners, including but not limited to customer support service ("**Bambu Services**").

For the purpose of this Policy, above products and services are collectively referred to as "**Bambu Lab Products and Services**". From time to time, we may develop new or offer additional services or products. Such new products and services will also be subject to this Policy, unless otherwise stated when they are launched by us.

Please note that this Policy is a legally binding agreement between you and Bambu Lab. By using the Bambu Lab Products and Services, you acknowledge that you have read, understood, and agreed to the terms of this Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Policy, you must NOT use the Bambu Lab Products and Services.

To help explain things as clearly as possible, we’ve added definitions for [Key Terms](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms). And if you have any questions about this Policy, you can contact us at privacy@bambulab.com.

**2\. Personal Data We Collect**
================================

[Personal Data](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms) refers to any type of information recorded electronically or otherwise relating to an identified or identifiable natural person, excluding information that has been anonymised. We may collect your Personal Data when you use Bambu Lab Products and Services or interact with us. Different types of data will be collected, depending on the service you use and your interactions with us. In some cases, you can choose not to provide such data, but this may prevent us from providing you with corresponding products or services, or we might not be able to respond to or resolve any issue you raise.

For the avoidance of doubt, when providing you with Bambu Lab Products and Services, we may also collect your personal data for statistics purpose, such as website visits, app downloads, and product sales volume, to understand how our products and services are used. The preceding statistics results do not constitute personal data.

We will collect and process your Personal Data through your purchase and/or use of the Bambu Lab Products and Services only for the purposes described in Section 3 and this Policy. The following are some examples of Personal Data we may collect:

Personal Data that you provide to us:
-------------------------------------

* **Account Information.** When you create a Bambu Lab & MakerWorld account (the "**Bambu Account**"), we collect your personal data that we need to create your account and that enables you to use the Bambu Lab Products and Service. This may include your email address, password, profile photo, profile name, User ID, user login token, bio, social media links and other information for account verification and use.
* **Contact Information.** When you purchase or request products or services from Bambu Lab, we collect your personal data necessary for processing of your order. This may include your name, email address, order information, mobile phone number, physical address, ZIP/postal code, country, and other contact information if necessary. We may process your physical address either to deliver notices to you when required by law or to deliver physical goods which you have purchased or requested.
* **Payment Information.** When you make a payment for our products or services, we will need to process your payment data. The exact personal data collected and used will vary depending on the payment method. This may include your name, mobile phone number, bank details, payment method type (credit or debit); if you use a debit or credit card, the card type, expiration date, and certain digits of your card number (Note: For security, we never collect or store your full card number); details of your payment history or other payment related information.
* **Transaction Information.** When you purchase or request products or services from Bambu Lab, we may also need to collect about your purchase record or transactions facilitated by us, including without limitation the details of your purchase history.
* **Job Application Information.** When you apply for a job position at Bambu Lab website, we may collect the job application information you provide (such as your CV, your first and last name, country, e-mail, and phone number).

Personal Data that that we collect when you use Bambu Lab Products and Services:
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------

When you use Bambu Lab Products and Services, we will collect your device information and how you and your device interact with our products and services. Such information may include:

* **Device Information.** This may include your Device name/model, Device serial number and/or other Device identifier from which your device could be identified, Device activation time, Device operating system, hardware model/version, network connection, crash data and user settings (such as region and language).
* **App Information.**  This may include app version, software identifier, app operation logs and app settings (such as region and language).
* **Usage Information.** This may include your [Internet or Network Activity Data](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms), such as products and services interaction, IP addresses, or browsing information collected through Cookies (To learn more, please read our [Cookie Policy](https://bambulab.com/policies/cookie-policy)); [Printing Operation Data](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms) (such as printer control information and printer operation information); performance data and diagnostic data; and other usage data.
* **Print Information.** This may include the G-code data and configuration information, printing settings, model picture, plate thumbnails in each print job forwarded to the 3D printer in order to print successfully and display the print information of 3D Model in each client ("**Printing Files**") and other information related to the print job we may store, including start times, finish times, filament consumption and other relevant information when you turn-on the function of print history reprinting (collectively "**Other Printing Information**"). You may choose to turn-on the function of Incognito Printing on Bambu Handy, we will then no longer store the relevant Print Information accordingly. ([_Learn more_](https://bambulab.com/policies/printing-information-statement))
* **Printer Camera Information.** This may include pictures or videos from both the micro lidar and chamber camera inside the printer. When you initiate a request for customer support service, we may collect your certain Printer Camera information if necessary and with your consent. We only collect Printer Camera Information when you voluntarily provide it to us, such as you voluntarily agree to join in the user experience improvement programme of our X series 3D printers. This data will be used solely for the purposes so permitted, and will not be used for any other purposes or shared with any third parties without your consent. For the avoidance of doubt, we only provide the transmitting channel services when you use the live view and/or remote video related functions through the built-in or added-on camera of our Devices and we will not collect or store any copies of the camera pictures or videos.
* **3D Model Files.** This may include your 3D model files (in 3D mesh or cad file), model description, model pictures, documentation files, license, model print settings and/or other 3D model related information. We will process the 3D Model Files only when you use the 3D Model community services of MakerWorld.
* **Fraud and Abuse Prevention Information.** Personal data that we need to collect for verification purposes to prevent fraud and abuse, including data of device trust and [Appeal Records](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms).

We may receive personal data about you from third-party sources, including:
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

* Third-party Account Information. When you register or log in to Bambu Lab’s online services using one of your existing Facebook, Apple, or Google accounts, we will collect your information from relevant third-party service providers to create your account. The service providers involved are Meta Platforms Ireland Limited., Apple Inc., and Google Ireland Ltd.
* Google Analytics Statistics Data. We receive Google Analytics statistics data from Google Analytics. Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Ireland Ltd. ("**Google**"). The configuration of Google Analytics has been modified by us to the measurement only function, unless separate consent for further advertising features has been given. Google Analytics uses a specific form of cookie, which is stored on your computer and enables an analysis of your use of our website. To learn more, please read our [Cookie Policy](https://bambulab.com/policies/cookie-policy).
* Airtable Form. We may collect user feedback through an Airtable form, which normally includes users' email addresses and feedback content.
* Other information we may receive from the third-party sources that provides the relevant services or supports.

**3\. How We Use Your Personal Data**
=====================================

In this Chapter, we set out:

* our purpose for processing your personal data (**"Purposes"**);
* our legal justifications (**"**[Legal Basis](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms)**"**) under data protection law, for each purpose;
* categories of personal data which we process for each purpose (**"Categories**").

We use your personal data only on the legal basis permitted by applicable privacy laws. According to applicable local laws, we may use your personal data for the following purposes under one or some of the legal bases: your consent; necessary to perform/enter into a contract between you and us; necessary to protect the legitimate interests of you or others; necessary to fulfil legal obligations; and necessary to protect the legitimate interests of enterprises.

Where we process your personal data to fulfil a legitimate interest, then we have carried out a balancing test to consider whether our interests are overridden by your interests and rights. You can ask us for more information about this by using the contact details at the end of the Policy.

Register and maintain your Bambu Account and enables you to use the Bambu Lab Products and Service
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to perform/enter into a contract between you and us following from the [General Terms of Use](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms) of the Bambu Lab (hereinafter the "**TOU**").
* Categories and Purposes: In order to use and maintain the customer account - Bambu Account, registration is required, during which we may process Account Information and other necessary data that you provide or subsequently add or modify in your Bambu Account.

Use of the Bambu Lab Websites
-----------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to perform a contract between you and us following from the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms).
* Categories and Purposes: We are committed to making the browsing experience on the Bambu Lab websites as superior and user-friendly as possible. In this respect, we may process Account Information, Contact Information, Payment Information and Usage Information related to your visit and use to the Bambu Lab Websites. For the use of the Cookies on Bambu Lab Websites, please read our [Cookie Policy](https://bambulab.com/policies/cookie-policy).

Purchase of the Bambu Lab Products and Services
-----------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to perform/enter into a contract between you and us following from the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms) as well as performance of the related legal obligations.
* Categories and Purposes: In order to successful process your purchase order and deliver the products or services you have requested, it is necessary for us to process your Account Information, Contact Information, Payment Information, and Transaction Information for the conclusion and performance of a contract.

Use of the Bambu Devices, Apps and Services
-------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to perform a contract between you and us following from the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms) and this Policy as well as performance of the related legal obligations.
* Categories and Purposes: In order to provide the device products and its related services such as the Apps, cloud service and other functionalities or features, it is necessary for us to process your Account Information, Contact Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, and Print Information.

Use of the MakerWorld services
------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to perform a contract between you and us following from the [Terms of Use of makerworld.com](https://makerworld.com/user-agreement) and also the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms).
* Categories and Purposes: We are committed to making the 3D Model community at makerworld.com as superior and user-friendly as possible and providing the 3D Model community services, functionalities, and features originally designed or intended, such as uploading and downloading model data, rating and commenting models, likes and collect models, reporting content that violates the [Terms of Use of makerworld.com](https://makerworld.com/user-agreement), win points reward and redeem prizes with points. In this respect, we may process the Account Information, 3D Model Files, Device Information, App Information and Usage Information, related to your visit and use of the MakerWorld.

Provision of technical and customer support services
----------------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing are necessary to perform a contract between you and us following from the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms) and this Policy as well as performance of the related legal obligations. We also reply on your consent as the legal basis in certain cases.
* Categories and Purposes: In order to deliver, activate, or verify the products and services you have requested, or perform changes and provide technical support and after-sales services for such offerings at your request and other support services such as diagnose, troubleshoot, and fix issues with the Bambu Lab Products and Service, it may be necessary for us to process your Account Information, Contact Information, Payment Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, 3D Model Files, Print Information, and Printer Camera Information.

Provide individualized or personalized user experience and content
------------------------------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: If you have given us your consent, we process the data mentioned below based on your consent otherwise our legitimate interests.
* Categories and Purposes: We may provide individualized user experience and content at your willingness and clearly disclosed to you at the time you provide personal information or with your consent. In this respect, we may process the Account Information, Contact Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, and 3D Model Files related to the specific individualized user service.

Marketing or advertising and other commercial activities
--------------------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is your consent.
* Categories and Purposes: After obtaining your consent or receiving your request, we may send you information about products and services you might be interested in, invite you to our promotional activities and market surveys, or send marketing information to you. In this respect, we may process the Account Information, Contact Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, and 3D Model Files related to the specific activity.

Evaluate and develop new features, technologies, and improvements to the Bambu Lab Products and Service
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: If you have given us your consent, we process the data mentioned below based on your consent otherwise our legitimate interests.
* Categories and Purposes: We are committed to continuous improvement of our products and services to customers. As such, we may carry out internal audit, data analysis and research; to conduct business planning, reporting, forecasting and analyse business operation efficiency and measure market shares; to conduct research and surveys and improve our products and services. In this respect, we may process the Account Information, Contact Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, 3D Model Files, Print Information and Printer Camera Information related to the specific activity.

Security, Fraud, and Abuse Prevention
-------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing are necessary to perform a contract between you and us following from the [TOU](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms), the [Terms of Use of makerworld.com](https://makerworld.com/user-agreement) and this Policy, performance of the related legal obligations and the Legitimate Interest of our customers and enterprises.
* Categories and Purposes: In order to keep the Bambu Lab Products and Service secure and to detect and prevent fraud, and improve our loss prevention and anti-fraud programs, we will process the Fraud and Abuse Prevention Information.

Recruitment
-----------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is your consent.
* Categories and Purposes: To assess your application for the job offered, we will communicate with you within the recruitment process. Based on your consent will ask you about your experience during the recruitment process. In this respect, we will process the [Job Application Data](https://bambulab.com/policies/key-terms).

Comply with Applicable Local Laws/Regulations
---------------------------------------------

* Legal Basis: The legal basis for personal data processing is necessary to fulfil legal obligations and necessary to protect the legitimate interests of customers or enterprises.
* Categories and Purposes: We may have to take certain actions based on the requirement of applicable laws and regulations, for example, fulfil e-commerce online management obligations, take appropriate action with reports of intellectual property infringement and inappropriate content, to establish, exercise, or defend legal claims. In this respect, we may process the Account Information, Contact Information, Device Information, App Information, Usage Information, 3D Model Files, Print Information, and Fraud and Abuse Prevention Information related to the specific activity.

**4.Your Privacy Rights**
=========================

We protect your rights over your personal data in accordance with GDPR and other applicable laws.

Some of these rights apply generally, while others will only apply in certain circumstances. Depending on the scenario, these rights may be subject to some limitations. We will be responsible for responding to your request within the relevant periods provided by law.

Below we have listed your rights regarding your personal data, including a description of the right ("**Right**"), and instructions on how to exercise the right ("**How to exercise**"). For each right, we also specify the circumstances in which it applies, which may include the required Legal Basis.

Be Informed (Art. 13/14 GDPR)
-----------------------------

* Right Be informed of the personal data we process about you and how we process it.
* How to exercise: You will be informed of the personal data we process about you and how we process it through this Policy, information provided to you when you use Bambu Lab Products and Services, or by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right of Access (Art. 15 GDPR)
------------------------------

* Right：Request access to the personal data we process about you.
* How to exercise: You may request access and a copy of your personal data from Bambu Lab by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.

When you download your data, you will receive the information about your data that Bambu Lab has to provide under Article 15 of the GDPR.

Right of Rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)
-------------------------------------

* Right：You may request that we amend or update your personal data where it’s inaccurate or incomplete.
* How to exercise：You can edit your Account data by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right of Erasure ("Right to be Forgotten") (Art. 17 GDPR)
---------------------------------------------------------

* Right：You may request us to erase certain of your personal data.

For example, you can ask us to erase the personal data:

* which is no longer needed by us in relation to the purpose for which they were collected or otherwise processed;
* which we have been processing based on the legal basis of consent, provided that you withdraw your consent;
* Which has been unlawfully processed by us (if any);
* which you have objected to process (see Section Object in Chapter 4 Your Privacy Rights below); or
* in other scenarios stipulated by law.

In certain situations, Bambu Lab is unable to delete your personal data in responding to your requests, including:

* when such personal data is still necessary to be processed to achieve the purpose we collected it for;
* Bambu Lab’s interest in using the data overrides your interest in having it deleted (e.g., when we need to process the personal data to protect our services from fraud);
* Bambu Lab has a legal obligation to keep relevant personal data; or
* Bambu Lab needs the personal data to establish, exercise or defend itself from a legal claim (e.g., when there’s an unresolved dispute relating to your account).

* How to exercise：You can request to delete your Personal Data by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right of Restriction (Art. 18 GDPR)
-----------------------------------

* Right：You may request restrictions on processing your personal data where:

* You are challenging the accuracy of the information;
* The information has been unlawfully processed, but you are opposing the deletion of that information;
* We no longer need your information for a specific purpose, but such information is required by the data subject for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims; or
* You have objected to our processing and we are assessing your objection request (See Section Right to Object in Chapter 4 Your Privacy Rights below).

You may request us to stop processing your personal data temporarily or permanently.

* How to exercise：you can exercise your right to restriction by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right to Object (Art. 21 GDPR)
------------------------------

* Right：You may object to our processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. This right applies when we are performing a task in the public interest, pursuing our legitimate interests or those of a third party or when you object to processing of your personal data for direct marketing purpose.
* How to exercise：You may use controls on the Bambu Lab Services to switch off or adjust some features which process your personal data. See the end of this section on how you can control tailored advertising, or contact us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right of Portability (Art. 20 GDPR)
-----------------------------------

* Right：You may request a copy of your personal data in electronic format and the right to transmit that personal data for use in another party’s service, when we are processing your personal data on the Legal Basis of consent or performance of contract. Bambu Lab will try to respond to your request to the extent possible.
* How to exercise：for information about how to exercise the right to portability, please See Section Right of Access above.

Not Be Subject to Automated Decision Making (Art. 22 GDPR)
----------------------------------------------------------

* Right：You have the right not be subject to a decision based solely on automated decision making (decisions without human involvement), including profiling, where the decision would have a legal effect on you or produce a similarly significant effect.
* How to exercise：Bambu Lab does not engage in this type of automated decision-making so far when providing the Bambu Lab Products and Service.

Withdrawal of Consent (Art. 7 GDPR)
-----------------------------------

* Right：You have the right to withdraw your consent from us on processing your personal data. You can implement your right of withdrawing your consent when Bambu Lab is processing your personal data on the Legal Basis of consent.
* How to exercise：You can adjust the relevant control on Bambu Lab, or contact us at privacy@bambulab.com.

Right to Lodge a Complaint (Art. 77 GDPR)
-----------------------------------------

* Right：You may contact the European Data Protection Board ("**EDPB**") for Privacy Protection or your local data protection authority about any questions or concerns regarding your personal data.
* How to exercise：You can find the EDPB’s details [here](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/about-edpb/members_en). You can also go to the website of your local data protection authority to lodge a complaint.

When you want to implement your rights mentioned above, we kindly ask you to:

* Submit requests through the channels we provided above.
* Provide sufficient information for us to verify the identities (to ensure those who initiate the requests are the data subjects themselves or those authorised by them).
* Ensure that the requests are specific and feasible.

We will make every effort to respond within one month upon receiving a request to access personal data. This period may be extended if necessary, depending on the number of requests and their complexity. If the request period is to be extended, we will notify you of the situation and reason for delay. In the event of any time conflict between this section and local laws/regulations, the latter shall prevail.

After a request is submitted, we will review your request and decides whether to accept your request.

We may reject your request in the following circumstances:

* Applicable laws do not grant relevant rights to data subjects;
* The identity of the requester cannot be verified;
* The request cannot be verified or is out of scope, especially when requests are sent repeatedly;
* The requested information is related to the compensation that we will make or receive as a result of an ongoing dispute, and the disclosure of such information is likely to damage our interests;
* Other situations stipulated by laws.

If we reject a request from a data subject, we will provide a formal explanation to you.

If none of the situations described in section above occurs, we will honor the request. To increase the likelihood that the request will be accepted, please provide information which is as detailed as possible when submitting your request, such as the request type, specific content, information about the data subject (such as the account name you use for Bambu Lab Products and Services), and time frame in which the information was generated or processed.

Typically, we will not provide the following information:

* Information about others: Requests from data subjects may involve other individuals besides the data subject. We will not provide such information, unless authorized by the relevant individuals.
* Repeated requests: If the data subject initiates the same or similar requests related to one data subject for multiple times, and the required information has not changed since the last time we provided such information, we will not provide the copy of such information repeatedly in most cases. Additionally, we have no obligation to provide information that has been publicly available.
* Special Information: We will not disclose any Special Information in response to requests for accessing personal data. For the purpose of this Policy, Special Information refers to any confidential information of Bambu Lab (such as attorney/client communication), and information that actually constitutes legal opinion (irrespective of whether it is related to the lawsuit itself or related to information from court proceedings).

**5\. Sharing Your Personal Data**
==================================

This Chapter sets out who receives personal data which is collected or generated through your use of the Bambu Lab Products and Services from Bambu Lab.

**Publicly Available Information**
----------------------------------

The following personal data will always be publicly available on the Bambu Lab Websites, Bambu Apps and MakerWorld (collectively "**Bambu Platforms**") (except to any user you have blocked):

* your profile name;
* your profile photo;
* content you post on the Bambu Lab Platforms and any associated titles, details, descriptions and images;
* who you are following on MakerWorld;
* who is following you on MakerWorld;
* your social media links on MakerWorld;
* the model you like and model you collect on MakerWorld;
* your public 3D models on MakerWorld.

You can share certain personal data to third party platforms, like social media or messaging platforms. This includes:

* your profile information;
* any content you post on Bambu Lab Platforms and details about that content.

To ensure smooth user experience, Bambu Lab Products and Services may contain links to third-party websites, products, and services. We do not have control over third-party websites, products, and services, but you can choose whether to access these links or share personal data on third party platforms. Bambu also has no control over the privacy or data protection policies of the third parties, as such third parties are not bound by this Policy. Before sharing or submitting personal data to third parties, please read and refer to their privacy or data protection policies.

**Personal Data We May Share**
------------------------------

From time to time, in order to provide Bambu Lab Products and Services to you and to achieve the purposes as stated in Chapter 3 (How We Use Your Personal Data), we may share your personal data to other Bambu Lab affiliated companies and other third-party service providers. This may include:

* **Bambu Lab Affiliated Companies.** We may share your personal data to our affiliated companies or grant access to your personal data to them to provide Bambu Lab Products and Services to you, or to fulfill our contractual and legal obligations. For example, some of the systems through which we provide Bambu Lab Products and Services are operated by our affiliated companies; some of our affiliated companies also provide supporting or maintenance services to our Products and Services. Please see the name list of all the Bambu Lab affiliated companies [here](https://bambulab.com/en/global-affiliates).
* **Bambu Lab Partner Programme.** In the Bambu Lab Partner Programme, we permit the resellers ("**Bambu Lab Partners**") to sell our products via their online channels or offline channels.

* When you order our products through Bambu Lab Partners, the products are generally delivered by relevant Bambu Lab partner. To fulfill the transaction between you and Bambu Lab Partners, the Bambu Lab Partners will process your personal data as the data controller. For more information on how the Bambu Lab Partners will process your personal data, please refer to these Bambu Lab Partners' own privacy policy. You can usually find their privacy policy on their website homepage. Bambu Lab is not responsible for personal data processing activities conducted by Bambu Lab Partners mentioned above.
* Nevertheless, when you purchase our products through Bambu Lab Partners' online or offline channels, Bambu Lab is still the data controller regarding processing some of your personal data, including without limitation the Account Information, Device Information, App information, or Usage Information for the purposes described in Chapter 3 (How We Use Your Personal Data).
* When you require Bambu Lab Partners to provide customer support service, we may share the personal data we collect from you to Bambu Lab Partners for the purpose of responding to your requests. For such personal data, Bambu Lab, as the data controller, will ensure that Bambu Lab Partners will only process them as per Bambu Lab’s instruction.

* **Service Providers or Partners.** We engage service providers or partners to manage or support certain aspects of our business operations or Bambu Lab Products and Services on our behalf. These service providers or partners may be located in the US or other countries/regions, and they may provide services such as payment service, customer support, order fulfillment, product delivery, advertising and marketing activities, personalized services, technical services, data hosting, or customer satisfaction surveys. More information about our service providers or partners can be found [here](https://bambulab.com/policies/service-providers-or-partners)**.**

If the above technical service providers or partners process your data outside the European Economic Area ("**EEA**") and this means that your data may be transmitted to a country/region with a lower data protection standard than the European Union, Bambu Lab will take all reasonable steps to ensure equivalent data protection level for such personal data.

**Other Conditions as Required by Applicable Law**
--------------------------------------------------

Bambu Lab may disclose your personal information with or without further consent when permitted or required by applicable laws or regulations.

**6\. Data Retention**
======================

We keep your personal data only for the period necessary to provide you with Bambu Lab Products and Services and for achieving Bambu Lab's legitimate and essential business purposes, such as making data-driven business decisions about new features and offerings, complying with our legal obligations, or resolving disputes.

Below we provide some of the categories of our retention periods:

* **Data Retained until You Remove It.** It's your right to request that we delete certain of your personal data. See Section Erasure in Chapter 4 (Your Privacy Rights for more information).
* **Data that Expires after a Specific Period of Time.** We have set certain retention periods so that some data expires or will be deleted after a specific period of time.
* **Data Retained until Your Bambu Account is Deleted.** We keep some data until your Bambu Lab account is deleted. When your Bambu Lab account is deleted, your data will be deleted or be anonymized.
* **Data Retained for Extended Time Periods for Limited Purposes.** After your account is deleted, we may keep some data for a longer time period but for very limited purposes, such as fulfilling legal obligation.

**7\. Transfer to Other Countries**
===================================

Due to the global nature of our business, Bambu Lab shares personal data internationally with Bambu Lab affiliated companies, subcontractors and partners when carrying out the data processing activities described in this Policy.

Whenever we transfer personal data internationally, we will make sure that the data transfer complies with applicable law. We also ensure the personal data benefits from an adequate level of data protection when transferring your information outside of the EEA, the UK, or Switzerland by relying on:

* Adequacy Decisions. This applies when we transfer personal data to countries outside of the European Economic Area ("**EEA**") which have adequate laws to protect personal data, as determined by the European Commission under Article 45 GDPR (or equivalent decisions under other laws). 
* Standard Contractual Clauses ("**SCCs**"). The European Commission has approved contractual clauses under Article 46 of the GDPR that allows companies in the EEA to transfer data outside the EEA to countries without an adequacy decision. These (and their approved equivalent for the UK and Switzerland) are called SCCs. For example, we use SCCs to transfer the personal data described in Chapter 2 (Personal Data We Collect) to our data hosting provider located in the US. You can exercise your rights under the Standard Contractual Clauses by contacting us at privacy@bambulab.com.
* For a copy of these adequacy decisions or standard contractual clauses, please contact us via the details provided in Chapter 11 (Our Contact Information) below.

**8.Data Security**
===================

We're committed to protecting our users' personal data. We, with our best efforts, use certain physical, organizational, and technical security measures that are designed to improve the integrity and security of personal data that we collect and maintain. We use cryptographic technologies to ensure the confidentiality of data transmission and storage, and implement reliable protection mechanisms to protect data from attacks. We deploy access control mechanisms to prevent unauthorized to your personal data. In addition, we limit the number of authorised personnel and implement hierarchical permission management based on service requirements and personnel levels. Access to personal data will be logged and reviewed by authorised personnel on a regular basis. (You can find more information about our security measures at [https://wiki.bambulab.com/general/bbl-security](https://wiki.bambulab.com/en/general/bbl-security)).

However, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable and no system is ever completely secure thus we cannot and do not guarantee that your personal data will not be accessed, viewed, disclosed, altered, or destroyed by breach of any of our physical, technical, or organizational security measures.

If other individuals have access to your Bambu Account, then they may access your personal data, controls and the service available in your account. For example, you may allow someone to use your account on a shared device. It's your responsibility to only allow individuals to use your account where you're comfortable sharing your personal data with them. Anyone else's use of your Bambu Account may impact your personalized settings and be included in your data records. To protect your user account and privacy, we encourage you to:

use a strong password which you only use for your Bambu Account;

never share your password with anyone else;

limit access to your own computer and browser; and

log out each time you finish using the Bambu Lab Products and Service in a shared or public environment.

**9.Children**
==============

Bambu Lab Products and Services are not intended for children under the age of 16 or as specified by law in their jurisdiction. We will not knowingly collect personal data from these children. 

If you are under the age of 16 or as specified by law in your jurisdiction, do not provide any personal data to us. If we discover that we have collected personal data from a child under the age limit, we will delete it promptly. If you believe we might have collected personal data from a child under the age limit, contact us at [privacy@bambulab.com](mailto:privacy@bambulab.com).

**10.Changes to this Policy**
=============================

We change this Policy from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Policy without your explicit consent. If we make material changes on how we process your personal data, we will notify you by sending an email to the email address you provide or through a notice on the home page of our website. You may find the date when the Policy is last updated at the top of the page. You are responsible for ensuring we have an up-to-date active email address from you. Please also visit our website and read this Policy regularly to check any changes.

**11.Our Contact Information**
==============================

For any questions, requests or concerns about this Policy, please contact us by sending an email to [privacy@bambulab.com](mailto:privacy@bambulab.com), or by mailing to us at the following postal address:

_**MAKERWORLD SINGAPORE PTE. LTD.**_

Address: 103 TAMPINES STREET 86 #03-06 THE ALPS RESIDENCES SINGAPORE (528576).

**12\. Final provisions**
=========================

* This Policy forms an integral part of the [General Terms of Use](https://bambulab.com/policies/terms) of Bambu Lab.
* This Policy enters into effect on September 22, 2023.

Be the first to receive our latest product updates, newest offerings, and free product trials.

Sign Up

By signing up, you agree to Bambu Lab’s [Privacy Policy](https://bambulab.com/en/policies/privacy) and [Terms of use](https://bambulab.com/en/policies/terms).

Product

Community

Support

Software

Company

Partners

 GlobalEnglish

Copyright © 2024 Bambu Lab All Rights Reserved.

Do Not Sale or Share My Personal Information
